Adam Caplan

Boston, MA * (617) 855-5188 * apcaplan@gmail.com

Software engineer and international yoga teacher with a passion for learning and for helping others to be at their best. Over 15 years experience coaching, teaching, problem solving with diverse populations, and creating customized solutions to meet individual needs.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Fellow, General Assembly

Boston, Massachusetts

May 2019 - July 2019

- Completed 12 week/500+ hour immersive to hone skills in full-stack responsive web application development
- Built RESTful APIs to integrate data and UI
- Designed and built four single-page web applications with full CRUD actions, implementing mobile-first, responsive design – each within 5 business days:

Tic Tac Toe – a two-player tic tac toe game

Built with JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3/SASS, Bootstrap, and AJAX

Mindfulness Meditation Journal – a user-friendly app for journaling meditation experiences, tracking changes, and observing progress over time

- Built with JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3/SASS, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL
- Cloud-based deployment hosting using GitHub pages and Heroku

RESTaurant – a user-friendly, easy way for restaurants to track inventory

- Built on JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, AJAX, Handlebars, Bootstrap, NodeJS, ExpressJS, MongoDB
- Developed as a group project, leveraging SCRUM and other AGILE methodologies and team version control
- Completed MVP and project requirements in 3 business days

Sun Salutations – a fun way to learn, practice, and track yoga sun salutations!

• Full-stack application built with ReactJS, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Material-UI, and Ruby on Rails

Advanced Yoga and Meditation Teacher, Adam Caplan Yoga

Multiple locations in Thailand, India, and USA

October 2005 - present

- Offer workshops, retreats, trainings, and classes in diverse international communities, to over 500 students per year, with classes ranging in size from private one-on-one's to groups of over 100 students
- Assess students' goals and needs, develop individually tailored solutions
- Counsel, teach, train, and mentor yoga teachers

Academic and Test Preparation Coach, PrepMatters

Bethesda, Maryland

August 2003 - August 2007

- Booked over 3,000 hours tutoring students, ages 9-18, in academic subjects and for standardized tests
- Assessed student abilities; designed and implemented individualized plans to meet each student's needs; taught anxiety-relieving techniques
- Developed and implemented curricula for pro-bono student groups

SKILLS

Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Sass, jQuery, AJAX, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Express.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, Git / Github

EDUCATION

Boston University Boston, MA

Boston, MA
Bachelor of Arts,
English and Religion
Magna Cum Laude,
University Professors
Honors Program

Agama Yoga School

Koh Phangan, Thailand Yoga Philosophy and Practice, 2,500+ hours formal study

YOGA TEACHER CERTIFICATIONS

Hridaya Yoga Koh Phangan, Thailand (500 hours)

Agama Yoga School

Koh Phangan, Thailand (500 hours)

Kripalu Center Stockbridge, MA (200 hours)

Corps Member, City Year Boston